JYOTIRMOY GHOSH

SUMMARY

With over 5 years of experience as a project management associate in localization & interpretation within the healthcare, insurance, transportation & logistics industries. Through application of project management techniques, I have ensured the smooth execution of language & logistic projects & aided management in achieving the objectives

WORK EXPERIENCE

DATAMARK BPO SERVICE (Senior Executive) - JUNE 2018 - PRESENT

- Spearheaded Languageline interpretation services for client in hospitals, insurance, judicial system, & immigration domain, ensuring absolute precision & impeccable interpersonal skills during audio-video interpretation sessions; notable clients include UNITED HEALTH GROUP & MAXIMUS NY.
- Utilized Agile methodology to outline project objectives, scope, deliverables, stakeholders, milestones, & timelines while assigning & managing linguists, language specialists, & auditors in language services during project's lifecycle.

ARAMEX LOGISTICS(Project Coordinator) - JAN 2018 - MAY 2018

- Orchestrated the successful implementation of a logistics project in Dubai, resulting in a substantial increase in company revenue which led to its growth. Served as a pivotal member of the project management team, facilitating smooth operations by expertly managing scheduling, organizing project elements, negotiating change orders, & allocating budget..
- Utilised design analysis & lean methodologies to create a comprehensive oneyear plan that aligned with business objectives. Supported the managers throughout all the phases of project planning & execution, including monitoring program RAIDs, & managing a budget of 1M\$ in FY 18-19.
- Conducted regular Skype meetings to proactively identify & manage potential project risks & uncertainties. Provided daily updates to senior leadership team on project progress & data insights. Leveraged Jira, Excel, & MS Office Suite to efficiently manage & track project task timelines.
- Implemented effective change strategies on a bi-weekly basis, conducting meetings to manage the project scopes, finances, risk and deliverables.
- Delivered regular project status & reports to the client, highlighting key accomplishments, defects, & risks, as well as identifying opportunities for improvement. Mentored interns & fostered a collaborative learning environment.

CERTIFICATIONS

PMI-ACP - https://simpli-web.app.link/e/beRUXjZKcrb || PMP BASICS - https://simpli.app.link/e/beRUXjZKcrb || SCRUM MASTER - https://simpli.app.link/ || SCRUM MASTER - https://simpli.app.link/ || Six-Sigma(DMAIC) - https://simpli.app.link/oftVdxIRDrb || CCBA - https://simpli-web.app.link/e/kuvUndqLcrb || CAPM - https://simpli-web.app.link/e/kuvUndqLcrb

SKILLS

Jira, Sql, Excel, Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, Leadership, Scope Analysis, Risk Management Stakeholder Management, Confluence, Kanban, Time Management, Java, DSA, LINUX, Rdbms, SpringBoot, Hibernate, Microservices, MVC, ReactJS, Visual Studio Code.

EDUCATION

PHCET, Rasayani, Panvel (University of Mumbai accredited) - B.E. ELECTRONICS (2013 - 17) Indira Gandhi National Open University - Master's of Arts (English Literature) (2020 - 2022) Software Development Engineering - Great Learning (Post-Graduate Program) - Pursuing.